Thomas P. Bradbury

Experienced CAD Drafter, Electrical Designer

Philadelphia, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Thomas-P-Bradbury/373964d5dc689265

I am a motivated individual with more than 25 years of experience in Computer Aided Drafting and Design with a desire to advance my career. I have a genuine concern for achieving total project satisfaction.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Integrated Systems Specialist, Electrical Design/Drafter, AutoCAD Operator

Lutron Electronics - Coopersburg, PA - March 2011 to October 2012

Coopersburg, PA, Contract Position 03/11 to 10/12

Position: Integrated Systems Specialist, Electrical Design/Drafter, AutoCAD Operator

Create Submittal Packages for Customer approval. Including Cover Pages, Bill of Materials, Sequence of Operations, One Line Wiring Diagrams, Loop Layout Drawings, Wall Station Button Engraving Sheets and Product Specification Sheets.

Duties include: Layout One Line Wiring Diagram Drawings showing Lutron Lighting Control Systems with associated equipment and devices using Bill of Materials and Take-off spreadsheets. Create Loop Layout drawings showing lighting control zones using Floor Plan drawings provided by customers/contractors and Take-off spreadsheets. Create Lighting Control Panel Schedules using Microsoft Excel. Create individualized Wall Station Button Engraving sheets when necessary. Also, assisted Project Managers with maintaining project schedules and integrity.

Jobs types include new construction and retrofit of Schools, Colleges and Universities, Hospitals, Commercial and Industrial facilities, Office Buildings, Government Office Buildings, Courts and Prison Facilities, Hotels, as well as Private Residences.

Siemens Electrical Contractor

Schlesinger - Maspeth, NY - July 2008 to July 2009

Position: Electrical Design/Drafter, AutoCAD Operator, IBEW Local #3 Member

Create design drawings for electrical engineers and designers, develop detailed electrical construction drawings from design drawings, and develop as-built drawings depicting the final constructed project from information provided by the field supervisors, project managers and electricians.

Work was centered on and performed at the Croton Water Treatment Facility, Bronx, NY

Electrical Design/Drafter, AutoCAD Operator

Giovanetti Shulman Associates - Broomall, PA - June 2007 to March 2008

Project Manager, Engineer

- 2006 to 2007

Layout electrical construction drawings using AutoCad Building Systems Electrical 2006 and 2007. Electrical power distribution equipment, branch wiring, wiring devices, lighting fixtures, etc. as well as fire alarm system equipment and wiring, using architectural background drawings. Duties include CAD drafting of electrical construction drawings. Updating drawings per Project Manager, Engineer or Designer's redline changes and customer changes. Plotting of drawings, copying prints and maintaining job drawing and project files.

Typical assignments included new and renovated hotels and casinos, high-rise residential housing, assisted living facilities, recreational facilities, educational and financial institutions, medical facilities, office buildings and complexes, etc.

Electrical Design/Drafter, AutoCAD Operator

Larry C. McCrae, Inc - Philadelphia, PA - August 2005 to November 2006

Layout electrical construction drawings using AutoCad 2006, electrical power distribution equipment, branch wiring, wiring devices, lighting fixtures, etc. as well as fire alarm system equipment and wiring, using architectural background drawings. Duties include CAD drafting of electrical construction drawings. Updating drawings per Project Manager's redline changes and customer changes. Equipment quantity take-offs. Plotting of drawings, copying prints and blueprints, maintain job drawing and project files.

Work was centered on The Symphony House Luxury High-Rise Condominiums and Enon Tabernacle Baptist Church in Philadelphia.

Electrical Design/Drafter, AutoCAD Operator

RS Electrical Contractors, Inc - Buena, NJ - August 1997 to July 2005

Responsibilities

Layout electrical construction drawings using AutoCad 2004, electrical power distribution equipment, branch wiring, wiring devices, lighting fixtures, etc. as well as fire alarm system equipment and wiring, using architectural background drawings. Duties include CAD drafting of electrical construction drawings. Updating drawings per Project Manager's redline changes and customer changes. Equipment quantity take-offs. Plotting of drawings, copying prints, making blueprints, documentation control, filing, maintain job drawing and project files. Computer maintenance, including hardware and software installation, troubleshooting and repair, computer network maintenance, including running computer cables, installing new computers, system backup and restoration of files, operating systems, etc. Order supplies and provided input and recommendations as to the purchase of equipment for Drafting Dept. Typical assignments included commercial and industrial warehouses and distribution centers with and without office space.

Electro-Mechanical Drafter, AutoCAD Operator

LCR Electronics, Inc - Norristown, PA - April 1993 to June 1997

Responsible for assisting Engineers with design of custom EMI/RFI Powerline and Communications filters for use in commercial and military applications. Engineering support, parts research and requisitioning, drafting (using AutoCad, Rel. 13), documentation control, manufacturing package preparation and quality control. Other responsibilities include training new drafting employees, computer hardware maintenance, file database maintenance, peripherals and supplies recommendation and purchasing. Responsible for updating an obsolete parts catalogue library for use by the Engineering Department. Also created an extensive parts library, using AutoCad, for use by the Drafting Department.

PCB/PWB Designer, CAD Operator

ASI Division, Cadence Design Systems, Inc - Blue Bell, PA - February 1988 to February 1992

Responsible for design of low and high density thru-hole and surface mount, single-sided, double-sided and multi-layered printed circuit boards for use in commercial and military applications. Also, the drafting of said printed circuit boards fabrication and assembly drawings. Other responsibilities included document preparation and control, CAD/CAM applications, schematic capture, fabrication and assembly drawings, detail drawings, knowledge of controlling specifications, project coordination and implementation. All work was done using CADAM Mainframe, MicroCadam, AutoCad (Rel. 10), and CADRA drafting packages.

EDUCATION

Associates Degree in Specialized Technology in Electro-Mechanical Drafting and Design

American Institute of Drafting - Philadelphia, PA 1985 to 1988

Certificate of Completion in Basic Electronics, Sheet Metal Shop Practices

A. Philip Randolph Career Center (Vocational/Technical School) - Philadelphia, PA 1979 to 1981

High School Diploma in Academic Studies

Cardinal Dougherty High School - Philadelphia, PA 1977 to 1981

SKILLS

- AutoCAD 9 through 2010, Windows, Microsoft Office products and various other software Background in electro-mechanical drafting and design Able to work independently, under pressure and meet deadlines
- Demonstrated accuracy, attention to detail and ability to work well in team environment Strong problem solving and analytical skills Excellent communication, organizational and interpersonal skills